[{"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ca", "question": "Which Shakespeare play tells a love story between a Capulet and a Montague?", "answer": "Romeo and Juliet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2157531a458464a93c45f", "question": "What is the name given to people who make arrows?", "answer": "Fletcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc6", "question": "What synthpop instrumental was the biggest hit for \"Hot Butter\"?", "answer": "Popcorn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d68", "question": "In the Bible, who is the mother of the prophet Samuel?", "answer": "Hannah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c674", "question": "Downy, Hairy and Pileated are species of what bird?", "answer": "Woodpecker", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c5", "question": "What is the capital of the Canadian province of Manitoba?", "answer": "Winnipeg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa9", "question": "What is Diazepam better known as?", "answer": "Valium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae4", "question": "What current-day country was writer, neurologist and psychiatrist Viktor Frankl born in?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba76", "question": "What is the better known name of cosmetics queen born Josephine Esther Mentzer?", "answer": "Estee Lauder", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd18b6a29d03ab85b632b31", "question": "Who said, \"If you can't explain it to a six year old, you don't understand it yourself\"?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2eb", "question": "What US state has been led by Hannibal Hamlin and Edmund Muskie?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5a", "question": "What president delivered his \"Fourteen Points\" speech in Congress in 1918?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a125", "question": "What do \"Tom\", \"Dick\", and \"Harry\" refer to in the film \"The Great Escape\"?", "answer": "The escape tunnels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfad79dc5ec6cd98a8312", "question": "What American artist is best known for abstract, white-on-white paintings?", "answer": "Robert Ryman -- Most of his works feature abstract brushwork in white or off-white paint on square canvas or metal surfaces.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c5", "question": "In 1996 and 2000, who was the presidential nominee from the Green Party?", "answer": "Ralph Nader", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6000ecbf9a72b906b34e3ce5", "question": "How is the groundnut better known?", "answer": "Peanut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddcad6ce05a3942286d9e", "question": "Who hosts the Potterwatch pirate radio show?", "answer": "Lee Jordan hosts Potterwatch to advise listeners on defenses against Lord Voldemort.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d06211a1c922dd1ac64a8", "question": "What year did Robert A. Heinlein published the novel \"The Number of the Beast\"?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339564", "question": "Which famous muscleman directed the 1992 made-for-TV movie, Christmas in Connecticut?", "answer": "Arnold Schwarzenegger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c92c", "question": "The comma bacillus causes what disease?", "answer": "Cholera", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdc1375469bb8041d07a07f", "question": "What did the \"lemon campaign\" advertise in the 60's?", "answer": "Volkswagen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe522ae1bf59ab7d2e380e9", "question": "\"100% Squeezed Sunshine\" has been which company's ad slogan?", "answer": "Tropicana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338abe", "question": "Which author and philosopher is known for his works The Plague, The Outsider and The Fall?", "answer": "Albert Camus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b728", "question": "How many reindeer does Santa have?", "answer": "Nine if you include old Rudy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7a04ff048f679a45abe5", "question": "Where is the uvula located?", "answer": "In the throat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba85", "question": "Who succeeded Tom Brokaw as anchor on NBC\u2019s Nightly News in 2004?", "answer": "Brian Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ad", "question": "What does the legal term \"Persona non grata\" mean?", "answer": "An unwelcome person", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b494", "question": "Which country hosted the 1900 Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a92820565ad31a57c7fe", "question": "Who was the first director of the FBI?", "answer": "J. Edgar Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1e", "question": "What author created the land of Fantastica?", "answer": "Michael Ende", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "591c37e9815febcc896f9276", "question": "What is the fifth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Leo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937eeec08d98002fdd633db", "question": "What is 2000 in Roman Numerals?", "answer": "MM", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600cc03c6de0eb824d4052d8", "question": "How did the Pacific Ocean get its name?", "answer": "Portuguese explorer, Ferdinand Magellan named it \"Mar Pacifico\", which means \"peaceful sea\" in both Portuguese and Spanish.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a69c", "question": "The Canadian city of Windsor is linked to what US city by the Ambassador Bridge?", "answer": "Detroit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ac", "question": "The troposphere, stratosphere and mesosphere all make part of the Earth's what?", "answer": "Atmosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76685eec85e375820b282", "question": "What is the Japanese word for \"dog\"?", "answer": "Inu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fcd", "question": "The word \"Cyberspace\" appeared for first time in which William Gibson publication?", "answer": "Burning Chrome", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d7", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his role in the film 'The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b0ea45964118b2bb3809d1", "question": "What year did the \"ILOVEYOU\" virus began infecting computers worldwide?", "answer": "2000", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae1c", "question": "How many battleships were sunk during the attack of Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "5", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b000", "question": "During the 1700s, what was the main industry on Nantucket Island?", "answer": "Whaling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b784", "question": "Who invented machine-spun cotton candy?", "answer": "William Morrison", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3728ff048f679a45ab15", "question": "The diameter of an atom is measured in which units?", "answer": "Angstroms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc8", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Passepartout?", "answer": "Phileas Fogg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9fe", "question": "What is the branch of medicine that deals with the care of infants and children?", "answer": "Pediatrics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae99", "question": "Established in 1607, what settlement was founded by John Smith in Virginia?", "answer": "Jamestown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7347aeec85e375820b235", "question": "Which US presidents signed the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson and John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae1", "question": "Hamlet was the Prince of which country?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef653f6ce05a3942286e6a", "question": "What director founded the film production company named \"That's A Bad Hat Harry\"?", "answer": "Bryan Singer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec26208dc25ca9e12ef647", "question": "Which country traditionally gives London's Trafalgar Square its Christmas tree?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339550", "question": "Who was Gordon Shumway?", "answer": "Alf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d76", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Novel Without a Hero\"?", "answer": "Vanity Fair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ae958a574a5ce6b56b8256", "question": "What is the name of the raven in George Orwell's \"Animal Farm\"?", "answer": "Moses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c80b", "question": "Which of the four bases of DNA isn't found in RNA?", "answer": "Thymine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd81", "question": "With what team did Dennis Rodman win his first NBA title?", "answer": "The Detroit Pistons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c3721815febcc896f926d", "question": "What is a group of mallards in flight called?", "answer": "A Sord", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a869", "question": "Andorra is landlocked by what two countries?", "answer": "France and Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfce", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"U\"?", "answer": "Uniform", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a48e", "question": "What is the largest city of Madeira?", "answer": "Funchal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc37", "question": "What US city was basketball player Michael Jordan born in?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339875", "question": "In Disney's \"The Jungle Book\", what kind of animal is Mowgli raised by?", "answer": "Wolves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dc04e748bb36357acdda", "question": "What is the name of the ship Darwin sailed on when he made his historic visit to the Gal\u00e1pagos Islands?", "answer": "H.M.S Beagle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b09d", "question": "What city hosted the 2012 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c514", "question": "A hair that curls back on itself and penetrates the skin is known as what?", "answer": "Ingrown", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f735ca9e54d890926f6f0", "question": "What word comes from the name of a hot spring in Iceland?", "answer": "Geyser -- The term refers to a specific geyser named Geysir, which means \"the gusher\" from the Old Norse \"geysa\" for \"to gush\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f16985f7c52aae91cc07d2", "question": "Who started the first commercial pretzel bakery in the US?", "answer": "Julius Sturgis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae70", "question": "What US first lady was nicknamed \"the Silver Fox\"?", "answer": "Barbara Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c35", "question": "The Grammy Awards are depicted by what gold plated musical object?", "answer": "The gramophone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d61", "question": "Who wrote the 1963 novel \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Pierre Boulle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beaf", "question": "How many hole cards is each player dealt in Texas Hold 'Em?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20c", "question": "Which country hosted the first Olympic Games after World War I?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b875e662d71a53651024", "question": "When was \"Silent Night\" written?", "answer": "1818", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c16d", "question": "What's the international radio code word for the letter \"M\"?", "answer": "Mike", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab9d", "question": "What was Saint Petersburg called for a short period of time before being renamed to Leningrad?", "answer": "Petrograd", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933c", "question": "Who was JR Ewing's brother on the TV show \"Dallas\"?", "answer": "Bobby Ewing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e338fe83fe1f2a824ba9", "question": "Why was the Japanese capture of Rangoon such a bitter loss for the Allies?", "answer": "As a major seaport, it was an excellent supply point", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7caa1877e98cb97778a08", "question": "In which country will you find the cities Toledo and Granada?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e38", "question": "In what film is General Jack Ripper obsessed with America's \"precious bodily fluids\"?", "answer": "Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c2", "question": "What is Mickey Mouse's dog's name?", "answer": "Pluto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339383", "question": "How long does a replicant live for in the movie \"Blade Runner\"?", "answer": "Four years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d2", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Colorado river?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa3f", "question": "What is the capital of China?", "answer": "Beijing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42a", "question": "In what country would you see \"whirling dervishes\"?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c0", "question": "Wanamaker's of Philadelphia first US store to install what in 1878?", "answer": "Electric illumination", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049c1ccf93664eb10486a4", "question": "In which North American city would you find Joe Shuster Way?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600242004be4723ccac22180", "question": "Which Irish poet, born in 1865, was instrumental in the founding of the Abbey Theatre in Dublin?", "answer": "William Butler Yeats", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60062c20c9d816e292245c29", "question": "English artist Andy Brown created a portrait of Queen Elizabeth II using what?", "answer": "English artist Andy Brown created a portrait of Queen Elizabeth II out of 1000 used and unused tea bags.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc48", "question": "Who was Andre Agassi's greatest tennis rival in the 1990s?", "answer": "Pete Sampras", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac82", "question": "Who founded the city of Philadelphia?", "answer": "William Penn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b85d", "question": "If you had pogonophobia what would you be afraid of?", "answer": "Beards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8b94ec223966ae8f8840", "question": "\"Mi Reflejo\" was a Spanish-speaking album released by which famous musician?", "answer": "Christina Aguilera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5f", "question": "What coastal Atlantic US state has \"The Shag\" as their official state dance?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c910", "question": "What is a group of toads called?", "answer": "Knot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c980", "question": "What sort of a creature is a Boto?", "answer": "Dolphin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42b", "question": "In which country is the city Marrakesh located?", "answer": "Morocco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c934", "question": "The Campbell-Stokes Recorder measures what with a glass ball?", "answer": "Sunshine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b335", "question": "What brand of melty cheese was first introduced to the mass market in 1928?", "answer": "Velveeta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975b", "question": "Who plays the last man on Earth in I Am Legend?", "answer": "Will Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3d", "question": "What actor died nine days after completing his final movie \"Soylent Green\"?", "answer": "Edward G. Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cfedbb53d1af658864f7", "question": "What was the name of the toy store in the film \"Home Alone 2\"?", "answer": "Duncan\u2019s Toy Chest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc0", "question": "What mythical bird dies in flames and is reborn from the ashes?", "answer": "Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ff", "question": "John Paul Jones' frigate was named \"Bonhomme Richard\", after whose pen name?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e1a506d333868d34d729", "question": "Which country did England send convicts to between 1788 and 1868?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45c", "question": "Who succeeded Anthony Eden as Prime Minister in 1957?", "answer": "Harold Macmillan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfa", "question": "What was the name of King Arthur's sword?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfe", "question": "On what date did the \"Dennis the Menace\" comic strip debut in newspapers?", "answer": "March 12, 1951", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd2", "question": "The New Wave band Thompson Twins were named for characters in what comics series?", "answer": "The Adventures of Tin Tin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c8", "question": "What fruit is packed with the most calories?", "answer": "The avocado", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c88e6db22f44c2d77a29c43", "question": "Qeru Chay is a village in which country?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339728", "question": "Which cartoon Great Dane is the pet and lifelong companion of Shaggy Rogers?", "answer": "Scooby Doo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b48ae49076251badbeaa4", "question": "What space shuttle did John Glenn travel in when he returned to space?", "answer": "Discovery -- Glenn flew on\u00a0Space Shuttle\u00a0Discovery's\u00a0STS-95\u00a0mission in 1998.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbef76ce05a3942286ef9", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Heart of Glass\"?", "answer": "Blondie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af08", "question": "Who replaced Colin Powell as Secretary of State under president George W. Bush?", "answer": "Condoleezza Rice", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5921fd54a4edfd43a087adc9", "question": "How many holes can be found in the standard bowling ball?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6003951257a0e35c43f83891", "question": "Any color plus white is called what?", "answer": "A tint", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c3", "question": "Which year was Marilyn Monroe born?", "answer": "1926", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a2", "question": "What nation is home to the ancient Grand Canal?", "answer": "China", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a426", "question": "In which country would you find St. Basil's cathedral?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b69d", "question": "The name \"Otto\" is German for what?", "answer": "Wealth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c9", "question": "The eggs of what sturgeon are the preferred form of caviar?", "answer": "Beluga", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592eaec8f83302ff91e4648c", "question": "Mark David Chapman became famous for what in 1980?", "answer": "Shooting John Lennon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e0", "question": "How many honeybees does it take to make one teaspoon of honey?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa85f6ce05a3942286ecf", "question": "In the film \"Aliens\", what is Newt's birth name?", "answer": "Rebecca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b2de4fda37788a9a1dbe", "question": "Who directed the 1962 film \"Lawrence of Arabia\"?", "answer": "David Lean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd7f", "question": "What spice is named for the capital of French Guiana?", "answer": "Cayenne pepper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb3", "question": "What Big US East school took the cryptic name for its sports teams from the Greek word for \"what\"?", "answer": "Georgetown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a3", "question": "Who plays Pacey Witter on the TV show \"Dawson's Creek\"?", "answer": "Joshua Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96bc923c87fd04dd15e1e", "question": "Which sitting US President was first to travel by plane?", "answer": "Franklin D Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339067", "question": "Which children's character was created by Mary Tourtel?", "answer": "Rupert Bear", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff1409fb0ee8c595b6d399e", "question": "Which famous artist wrote his notes in mirror script?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b3234fbbf195a31e15d73aa", "question": "Which artist starred in the title role of the film \"Merry Christmas, Mr. Lawrence\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe521881bf59ab7d2e380e3", "question": "How many swimmers are in a medley relay team?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af07", "question": "Harry Truman became president at the end of what war?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f48", "question": "What naval hobbyist produced the landmark book \"All the World's Fighting Ships\" in 1898?", "answer": "Fred T. Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339218", "question": "What is the theme song of the TV show \"Friends\" called?", "answer": "I'll Be There for You by The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b937364247bf200fb889", "question": "Who made the song \"A Boy Named Sue\" popular in 1969?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd0", "question": "What NBA star made an ill-fated trip to Eagle, Colorado, in 2003 for knee surgery?", "answer": "Kobe Bryant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a94bc61d1b4d384d5d671", "question": "Who is Dana Elaine Owens more commonly known as?", "answer": "Queen Latifah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b8", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"I thought I'd get into shape, so i've been drinking nothing but milkshakes.\"?", "answer": "Krusty the Clown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66161a5bfecdd737e083b", "question": "What movie holds the record for most weeks at #1 at the box office?", "answer": "E.T.: The Extraterrestrial", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a676", "question": "What monument, located in Washington D.C., was once the tallest structure in the world?", "answer": "Washington Monument", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3e", "question": "What pitcher with four World Series rings its nicknamed \"El Duque\"?", "answer": "Orlando Hernandez", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedd9b96ce05a3942286d7b", "question": "What cartoon character is popular in Sweden during Christmas?", "answer": "Donald Duck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd3", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"soy\"?", "answer": "Japanese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdffbb61cf6db9ac4808cf7", "question": "What's the oldest university in England?", "answer": "Oxford University", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9baa1364247bf200fb89a", "question": "What is the fear of death known as?", "answer": "Necrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca3", "question": "Oliver Mellors was the proper name of what D.H. Lawrence title character?", "answer": "Lady Chatterley's Lover", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb6", "question": "Who was the first African American to play in an NBA game?", "answer": "Earl Lloyd", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a1e1d75b5a031299b74573b", "question": "The Okapi is native to which African country?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea3", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Alexander and Cookie?", "answer": "Blondie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce7", "question": "What is Mr. Snuffleupagus's given name?", "answer": "Aloysius", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad4", "question": "In 2004, what golfer ended Tiger Woods' reign as the number 1 men's player in the world?", "answer": "Vijay Singh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae9457574a5ce6b56b8248", "question": "Barbara, Carignan, Cinsaut, and Nebbilo are verities of what?", "answer": "Italian wine grapes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339231", "question": "Who wrote the \"Pink Panther\" theme music?", "answer": "Henry Mancini", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c19f", "question": "What year was tennis player, Martina Hingis, born?", "answer": "1980", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cf2f877e98cb97778a4c", "question": "What does the Red Sea get its name from?", "answer": "Algae blooms", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eae6df83302ff91e46488", "question": "What bird lays an egg that is roughly a quarter of its body weight?", "answer": "The Kiwi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c467fbde8045e484669b", "question": "What is the color of a giraffe's tongue?", "answer": "Bluish-black -- This dark color helps protect the tongue from the sun as giraffes spend as much as 12 hours per day eating.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e271fe83fe1f2a824b9f", "question": "Which country was the site of most of the Nazi extermination camps?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6fe", "question": "What decade was Girl Scouts of America formed in?", "answer": "1910s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec22b48dc25ca9e12ef62a", "question": "Which French singer and actor sings the theme song to Disney's film \"The Aristocats\"?", "answer": "Maurice Chevalier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec25e88dc25ca9e12ef643", "question": "Which former member of Genesis had a hit with \"One More Night\"?", "answer": "Phil Collins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592ead77f83302ff91e4647c", "question": "What was a Portuguese moidore?", "answer": "A gold coin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5f7", "question": "In which city is the world famous La Scala opera house?", "answer": "Milan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b6", "question": "Which was the first Space-ready Shuttle to be launched?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015faeefe83fe1f2a824c37", "question": "What is the name of the woman who single-handedly brought to ruins the strongest man ever, Samson?", "answer": "Delilah. Delilah is arguably the most ruthless woman ever. She connived with the Philistines to take Samson down.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3c6eff048f679a45ab3d", "question": "Catagelophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Being ridiculed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008b35cf842fa4c4ba9696", "question": "What composer wrote the \"Pomp and Circumstance\" marches?", "answer": "Edward Elgar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be61", "question": "Avian flu in China led to 2006 price hikes in what piece of sporting equipment?", "answer": "Badminton birdies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3357ff048f679a45aaec", "question": "What are the folds of skin on a cat's ears called?", "answer": "\"Henry's pockets\" or cutaneous marginal pouches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b42f", "question": "At what age did Alfred Hitchcock die?", "answer": "80", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339139", "question": "In pulp magazines, who was referred to as \"The Man of Bronze\"?", "answer": "Doc Savage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a4676c0f9723ab15cb53", "question": "How did police identify criminals before fingerprinting?", "answer": "Bertillon System", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b216", "question": "Who was assassinated by Yigal Amir?", "answer": "Yitzhak Rabin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133955e", "question": "Who is the star of the \"Tomb Raider\" video games?", "answer": "Lara Croft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c77cf8024f0f7a362efd54e", "question": "In \"The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time\", what are the names of the six races?", "answer": "Hylian, Kokiri, Goron, Zora, Gerudo, Shiekah.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339785", "question": "What was Sam Malone's nickname on the TV show \"Cheers\"?", "answer": "Mayday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133889a", "question": "Where did Gulliver find a race of tiny people?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e31", "question": "In the nursery rhyme \"This Little Piggy\", what meat did the third little piggy eat?", "answer": "Roast beef", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af69", "question": "During what war did thousands of Americans invade the shores of Normandy?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af25aa1b63e5727cf5a4855", "question": "Which song was featured in the 1991 film \"Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves\" and held the number one spot in the UK singles chart for 16 weeks?", "answer": "(Everything I Do) I Do It for You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c81afbde8045e48466cf", "question": "What are the tiny air sacs in the lungs called?", "answer": "Alveoli", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c941", "question": "What is a group of larks called?", "answer": "Exaltation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a2", "question": "What river flows through the city of Baghdad?", "answer": "Tigris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5b", "question": "Which British actor played Basil Fawlty in the TV show \"Fawlty Towers\"?", "answer": "John Cleese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c5", "question": "Who composed the song \"Rhapsody in Blue\"?", "answer": "George Gershwin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c829fbde8045e48466d1", "question": "The Horsehead Nebula can be found in what constellation?", "answer": "Orion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062a82c9d816e292245c19", "question": "What artist created a 43 ft sculpture of a West Highland White Terrier puppy?", "answer": "Jeff Koons (He was commissioned to create the piece for Arolsen Castle in Germany.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2cc", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Stormin' Norman\"?", "answer": "Norman Schwarzkopf", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe769d3eec85e375820b2b2", "question": "Where was \"Cibik Ridge\" in World War II?", "answer": "Bougainville Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a98e361d1b4d384d5d693", "question": "Which major lake is near the Ponderosa Ranch in the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Lake Tahoe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a106", "question": "What was the last film of director Stanley Kubrick?", "answer": "Eyes Wide Shut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c9", "question": "Which film featured the song \"Springtime for Hitler\"?", "answer": "The Producers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa0", "question": "What CCR front man made his solo concert debut at the first Farm Aid in 1985?", "answer": "John Fogerty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a00d6c0f9723ab15cb32", "question": "What year was the first black hole discovered?", "answer": "1971", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e80575de59ea584496feaa", "question": "Which actress played Emma Peel in the 1960s TV show \"The Avengers\"?", "answer": "Diana Rigg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe37ab70ada16518afdc05b", "question": "What did Nazi Germany use Zyklon B for?", "answer": "To kill people in concentration camps", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda4", "question": "What group's honor society is the Order of the Arrow?", "answer": "The Boy Scouts of America", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa4", "question": "Minsk is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b26", "question": "In \"Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs\", which dwarf's job is it to check the authenticity of the gems they mine?", "answer": "Doc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ccf7c7cb37b32637bdc44c9", "question": "What animal is an orb weaver?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a751", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Hawkeye State\"?", "answer": "Iowa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe766e3eec85e375820b28b", "question": "You can find Grand Teton National Park in which U.S. state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8dd", "question": "What name is given to the fraction part of a logarithm number?", "answer": "Mantissa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe937706bd93ce3a4e5f66d", "question": "Cynophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dogs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339078", "question": "What country is Puccini's opera, \"Turandot\", set in?", "answer": "China", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f2", "question": "What note is the highest string of a violin usually tuned to?", "answer": "E", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a89b", "question": "In 2004, a nine-foot-tall bronze statue of Bobby Bowden was dedicated in what US city?", "answer": "Tallahassee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3d65ff048f679a45ab4c", "question": "What is a male camel known as?", "answer": "Bull", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc122ec223966ae8f8865", "question": "The 1982 football game that birthed \"The Play\", was between which schools?", "answer": "Stanford and Berkeley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596df873f0cc2631d16a3c61", "question": "Florida Georgia Line\u2019s song, \"H.O.L.Y.\", is an acronym for what?", "answer": "High On Lovin\u2019 You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4edf406d333868d34d771", "question": "The musical score for Hitchcock's \"Psycho\" uses which instrument exclusively?", "answer": "Stringed instruments", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff145cab0ee8c595b6d39bb", "question": "Richard Bachman is a pen name used by which American author?", "answer": "Steven King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b36f751c3f17ccc40c8e0e", "question": "In the film \"The Sixth Sense\", what does Cole find in the box Kyra directed him to?", "answer": "A videotape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa55bbc73aa70ea0b70b26", "question": "In which Asian city is the historic waterfront called The Bund?", "answer": "Shanghai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1a", "question": "What author created Prydain?", "answer": "Lloyd Alexander", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc86", "question": "What color is the one-ball in a traditional billiards set?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa2", "question": "What rock epic begins \"The screen door slams, Mary's dress sways\"?", "answer": "Thunder Road", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c5f20775fa611bce67ce", "question": "What is currently the tallest building in the U.S.?", "answer": "One World Trade Center, NYC -- The skyscraper houses a museum and memorial to those lost in the September 11 terror attacks.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa3bddc73aa70ea0b70ae9", "question": "Where is the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier located?", "answer": "Arlington National Cemetery, Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7736ceec85e375820b307", "question": "Which U.S. state is closest to the Tropic of Cancer?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fffa61c73838c5c8a417f2d", "question": "What is the process by which a Komodo Dragon can reproduce asexually?", "answer": "Parthenogenesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c36ca815febcc896f926a", "question": "What drug is obtained from the cinchona tree?", "answer": "Quinine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c051", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Finland?", "answer": "Whooper swan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeab", "question": "Which Cuban President was overthrown by Fidel Castro in 1959?", "answer": "General Fulgencia Batista", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3780a0ada16518afdc04f", "question": "What part of a chocolate bunny should be eaten first according to a majority of Americans?", "answer": "Ears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cd40b2e685cf15b733e9888", "question": "What South American country's name comes from the Latin word for silver?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a78e20565ad31a57c7ea", "question": "Which US President was known as \"The American Cincinnatus\"?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb9", "question": "Who left his Air America radio show in 2007 to run for the US Senate?", "answer": "Al Franken", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b730", "question": "What variety of beans is used to prepare Boston baked beans?", "answer": "Navy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901e", "question": "In the comic strip, \"Blondie\", what was Blondie's maiden name?", "answer": "Boopadoop", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eff", "question": "What famous horse belonged to Dudley Do-Right?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd3d", "question": "What were the first modern Olympic pole vaulters' poles made of?", "answer": "Bamboo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c4", "question": "What element has the chemical symbol Au?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ccf78d0b37b32637bdc44bb", "question": "What is the name of Marvin and Trina's son in the musical \"Falsettos\"?", "answer": "Jason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd968de23c87fd04dd15e05", "question": "What did the BBC broadcast on the \"day without news\" in 1930?", "answer": "Piano music", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d3", "question": "What song was used as the theme for the Three Stooges\"?", "answer": "Three Blind Mice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339733", "question": "What is Rambo's first name?", "answer": "John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a209", "question": "What TV series was based on the series of books by Laura Ingalls Wilder?", "answer": "Little House on the Prairie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa95e73838c5c8a417f44", "question": "What is Podobromhidrosis?", "answer": "Bad smelling odor from sweat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8aad401dd7bf43be5e762", "question": "Which Thanksgiving favorite did Marcus L. Urann invent?", "answer": "Cranberry sauce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f7", "question": "What is believed to be created when a star collapses?", "answer": "A black hole", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96dca23c87fd04dd15e2f", "question": "Who sculpted Mount Rushmore?", "answer": "Gutzon Borglum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389bf", "question": "What did Hannibal Lecter say French people taste like?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab9", "question": "What gas is exhaled by humans?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339102", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Carmen\"?", "answer": "Georges Bizet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa5fb6ce05a3942286ec8", "question": "Who directed the film \"Home Alone?\"", "answer": "Chris Columbus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe522321bf59ab7d2e380e5", "question": "Who is the godmother of Kurt Cobain and Courtney Love's kid Francis Bean?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b25fe662d71a53650fd7", "question": "Botticelli's \"Birth of Venus\" features a goddess floating in the ocean on what?", "answer": "Seashell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac8b", "question": "Who designed the famous collection of buildings in Oak Park, Illinois?", "answer": "Frank Lloyd Wright", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4aa349076251badbeaba", "question": "Ancient Romans boiled vinegar and what to make an energy drink?", "answer": "Goat dung", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e3f3965cb9e8bda6821364", "question": "When was the Rosetta Stone found?", "answer": "1799", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8af", "question": "In what city would you find Centennial Olympic Park?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}]